A Guide to the Social Science Research Council records, Administration and Officers Files, Presidents' Office FA1827
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council records, Administration and Officers Files, Presidents' Office
1972-2001
Rockefeller Archive Center
Social Science Research Council
Prewitt, Kenneth
Featherman, David
Wakeman, Frederic, Jr.
Sutton, Francis X. (Francis Xavier)
FA1827
20.51 Cubic Feet 54 letter document containers
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged into 6 series:
1. General Office Files, 1979-1992
2. Outside Organizations, 1972-2001
3. David Featherman Files, 1979-1995
4. Executive Committee Meetings, 1980-1995
5. Presidents' Chronological Files, 1986-1993
6. Committee Overview Files, 1990-1995
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This material was transferred to RAC in 2016 and 2017 by the SSRC and ingested by RAC as Accessions 2016:003, 2016:007, 2016:009, 2016:010, 2016:074, 2017:018, and 2017:022.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains the files of the following SSRC presidents: Kenneth Prewitt (1995–1998), David Featherman (1989–1995), Frederic Wakeman, Jr. (1986–1989), Francis X. Sutton (Acting President, 1985–1986), and Kenneth Prewitt (1979–1985).
The collection consists of general SSRC office files, board meeting materials, SSRC committee project correspondence, correspondence and reports from grantmaking organizations regarding grants to the SSRC, general correspondence with foundations, SSRC President David Featherman's office files and trip files, files relating to the work of SSRC commiittees, executive committee meeting materials, and David Featherman's and Frederic Wakeman, Jr.'s chronological files.
Grants administration
- General Office Files, 1979-1992; 1; 1.9 Cubic Feet 5 letter document boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Contains SSRC staff meeting materials, Board of Directors meeting materials, Items (SSRC newsletters), memos and correspondence, and financial documents.
  - Staff Meetings, 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1-12)
    Minutes, memos, agendas, notes, etc.
  - Interoffice Memos, 1979-1980; 1982-1992 (Box 2, Folder 13-20, Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Memorandums to the Board, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Memos from Kenneth Prewitt and Francis X. Sutton, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Sub-tenant Agreement - Pepper, Gelbord and Roth, 1987-1991 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Staff Travel, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - SSRC Holiday Schedule, 1948-1988 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Exchange Account - Received, 1980-1987 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Expense Account - Received, 1979-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Office Matters and Items, 1983-1989 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Items, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Council Library - Books, Archives, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Board of Directors Correspondence - Committee on Problems and Policy Membership and Board Membership, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Committee on Problems and Policy Correspondence, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Committee on Problems and Policy and Board Appointments, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Issues for Board of Directors, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Possible Committee on Problems and Policy Members Memos, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Committee on Problems and Policy - Exciting Ideas, 1985-1986 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Board of Directors Correspondence, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Committee on Problems and Policy Correspondence, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Board Correspondence, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Board of Directors Appointment Letters, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Board Nomination Possibilities, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted - Executive Search - Open in 2029
  - Board of Directors Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 4, Folder 43-44)
  - Composition of the Board, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1986 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Board Resolution on the Retirement of Frederic Wakeman, Jr., 1989 June 6 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Board of Directors, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Board and Committee on Problems and Policy Mailing Lists, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Foundation Listings and Briefing Sheets from David Szanton, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Committee on Law and Social Science, 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Word Processor Administration, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Fugazy Express. Inc., 1983 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Frederic Wakeman's Calendars, 1984-1988 (Box 5, Folder 55-59)
  - SSRC Holiday Schedule, 1988-1990 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - SSRC Schedule of Meetings, 1982-1986 (Box 5, Folder 61)
- Outside Organizations, 1972-2001; 2; 10.63 Cubic Feet 28 letter document boxes
  Contains correspondence with outside organizations, including foundations, government entities, and other nonprofits. Correspondence pertains to the work of SSRC committees, grants to the SSRC, research interests, and conferences. The series also contains articles and publications, congressional testimony, meeting materials, project proposals, and grant reports, and grant applications.
  - Asia Society, 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Board of Foreign Scholarships, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Britannica, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Center for Social Research, Berkeley, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC), 1983-1992 (Box 6, Folder 66-69, Box 7, Folder 70-74)
    Correspondence by year
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) Nomination by Frederic Wakeman, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) Meeting, National Academy of Sciences, 1989 September (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) Meeting, 1986 June (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) - Humanities Panel, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) - Meeting, 1985 December 3 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) - Articles, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) - Membership Chinese Library Resource Panel, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China (CSCPRC) - Activities, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - Chinese Economic Studies, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - Chinese Economic Studies, Peking University, undated (Box 8, Folder 84)
  - Commission of the European Communities, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 85)
  - Committee to Promote Quantitative and Experimental Aspects of the Social Sciences, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 86)
  - Conference Board/Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES) - General, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 87)
  - Conference Board/Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES) - Location, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 88)
  - Conference Board/Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES) - Expenses, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 89)
  - Conference Board/Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES), 1985-1990 (Box 8, Folder 90-93, Box 9, Folder 94)
  - Council for International Exchange of Scholars (CIES) - Correspondence, 1983-1990 (Box 9, Folder 95-97)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, 1986-1993 (Box 9, Folder 98)
  - Council of Graduate Schools in the U.S., 1986 (Box 9, Folder 99)
  - Council on Library Resources, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 100)
  - Council of Professional Associations on Federal Statistics, 1985-1994 (Box 9, Folder 101)
  - Consortium of Social Science Associations (COSSA), 1985-1990 (Box 10, Folder 102)
  - Culture and Learning - Comparative Child Development Working Group, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 103)
  - Culture and Learning Meeting - Project, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 104)
  - Culture and Learning - Child Development in Sociocultural Context Workshop, 1989 October (Box 10, Folder 105)
  - Daedalus, Journal of the Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 106)
  - Department of Labor - Doctoral Dissertation Grant Program, 1979-1980 (Box 10, Folder 107)
  - Department of Labor - Contract Quality of Employment Survey, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 108)
  - Department of Education - Sutton Speech, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 109)
  - Education and Society in Late Imperial China Conference, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 110)
  - East-West Center, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 111)
  - Correspondence - Office of Foreign Secretary, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 112)
  - Foreign Policy Association, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 113)
  - Fellowship Grants List, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 114)
  - Fellowship Awards, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 115)
  - Fellowship Grants List, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 116)
  - Fulbright, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 117)
  - Geography and SSRC, 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 118)
  - Global Security Planning Group, Santa Fe Institute, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 119)
  - Graduate Institute of International Studies, Geneva, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 120)
  - Retreat/Hanover II Staff Meeting Correspondence, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 121)
  - Harvard Visiting Committee, 2001 (Box 11, Folder 122)
  - Department of Health, Education, and Welfare (HEW), 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 123)
  - Hu Sheng, President of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, Visit, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 124)
  - International Federation of Institutes for Advanced Study (IFIAS), 1987 (Box 11, Folder 125)
  - Interdisciplinary: The First Half Century Correspondence, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 126)
  - Institute for Research in Social Science Correspondence, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 127)
  - Institute of International Education, 1986-1991 (Box 11, Folder 128)
  - International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX), 1972-1991 (Box 11, Folder 129-134, Box 12, Folder 135-140)
  - International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX)-Joint Meeting of Board and Program Committee, 1979 November 10 (Box 12, Folder 141)
  - International Institutions and Cooperation Committee Proposal, 1986-1988 (Box 12, Folder 142)
  - United States Information Agency (USIA)/International Research and Exchanges Board (IREX), 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 143)
  - John Israel, Chinese Sexuality Series, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 144)
  - Glenn Johnson's Agricultural Development Project, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 145)
  - Linguistic Society of America, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 146)
  - Mansfield Center for Pacific Affairs Correspondence, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 147)
  - Steven Mosher, Stanford, 1985-1986 (Box 13, Folder 148)
  - Coalition for the Advancement of Foreign Languages and International Studies (CAFLIS), 1988 (Box 13, Folder 149)
  - Coalition for the Advancement of Foreign Languages and International Studies (CAFLIS) Working Groups Background Material, 1988 December 5 (Box 13, Folder 150)
  - National Foreign Language Center at Johns Hopkins University Advisory Meeting, 1987 May 6 (Box 13, Folder 151)
  - National Foreign Language Resource Center - Meeting Minutes, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 152)
  - National Archives Advisory Council, 1981-1984 (Box 13, Folder 153)
  - Coalition for the Advancement of Foreign Languages and International Studies (CAFLIS) - Working Group, Federal Support for International Competence, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 154)
  - International Education and Research - Foundation Meetings, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 155, Box 14, Folder 156-157)
  - National Institute of Health (NIH), 1990; 1994 (Box 14, Folder 158)
  - National Humanities Alliance (NHA), 1987-1994 (Box 14, Folder 159)
  - National Opinion Research Center (NORC), 1992 (Box 14, Folder 160)
  - National Council on Foreign Languages and International Studies (NCFLIS), 1979-1986 (Box 14, Folder 161-163)
  - National Council on Foreign Languages and International Studies (NCFLIS) - Executive Director Search, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 164)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) - Five-Year Outlook on Science and Technology, 1980-1983 (Box 15, Folder 165-166)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) - Five-Year Outlook on Science and Technology, Kenneth Prewitt Chapter, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 167)
  - Budget Authorization for National Science Foundation (NSF), 1979 (Box 15, Folder 168)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) - Five-Year Outlook on Science and Technology - International Studies, 1980-1990 (Box 15, Folder 169)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) - Survey Guidelines, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 170)
  - Federal Granting Agencies: Information about Submissions, 1976-1978 (Box 15, Folder 171)
  - New York City Area Studies (NYCAS) - Ad Hoc Planning Group for University Social Research on New York City - Funding Letters and Budget, 1983-1985 (Box 15, Folder 172)
  - New York City Area Studies (NYCAS), 1982-1983 (Box 16, Folder 173)
  - New York City Area Studies (NYCAS) - Ad Hoc Planning Group for University Social Research on New York City, 1983 May 5 (Box 16, Folder 174)
  - New York City Area Studies (NYCAS), 1983 (Box 16, Folder 175)
  - Kenneth Prewitt Testimony - Subcommittee on Science, Research, and Technology of the Committee on Science and Technology of the US House of Representatives, 1981 March 12; 1986 (Box 16, Folder 176)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) Budget - House of Representatives Testimony, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 177-179)
  - John M. Ashbrook Testimony - Kenneth Prewitt Response to George E. Brown, Jr., 1980 (Box 16, Folder 180)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) Budget FY 1981 and Press Letter, 1980 (Box 16, Folder 181)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) FY1982 Budget Authorization/Cuts, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 182)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Grants, 1973-1989 (Box 16, Folder 183-186, Box 17, Folder 187-193)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Draft Proposal Comments, 1986 (Box 17, Folder 194)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 17, Folder 195)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Annual Performance Report RI-20264-86, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 196)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Annual Performance Report RI-20115-82, 1987 (Box 17, Folder 197)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Annual Performance Reports, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 198)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) - Interim Performance Report RI-20264-86, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 199)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) - Application - RI-20414, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 200)
  - Mellon Foundation Grant to Joint Committee of Latin American Studies (JCLAS), 1978 (Box 18, Folder 201)
  - European Science Foundation (ESF) - Standing Committee on Social Sciences, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 202)
  - Andrew W. Mellon Foundation Appropriation, 1980-1990 (Box 18, Folder 203)
  - International Research - National Endowment For Humanities (NEH) - RI-20115-82, 1982-1985 (Box 18, Folder 204)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Correspondence, 1985-1993 (Box 18, Folder 205-207)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Report - RI-20264-86, 1989-1991 (Box 19, Folder 208)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Grant #EH-21465 - Institute on Modern Indonesia, Thai, Filipino, and Vietnamese Literature, 1991 (Box 19, Folder 209)
  - Economics Initiative, 1991-1994 (Box 19, Folder 210)
  - Immigration to the United States Program, 1992-1993 (Box 19, Folder 211)
  - Area Studies Meeting at Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 212)
  - Soviet Studies - Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, 1986-1988 (Box 19, Folder 213)
  - Latin American Studies - Andrew W. Mellon Foundation, 1978-1982 (Box 19, Folder 214)
  - Andrew W. Mellon Appointments - Staff Changes, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 215)
  - Ford Foundation Grant #8201035 - Core International Reports, 1986-1990 (Box 19, Folder 216-218)
  - Ford Foundation Grant #900-0504 International Predissertation Fellowship, 1990-1994 (Box 19, Folder 219)
  - Ford Foundation Grant #900-1354 - Preservation and Training of African Archives Staff, 1990-1993 (Box 19, Folder 220)
  - Ford Foundation Bangladesh Grant #900-1148, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 221)
  - Ford Foundation Grant #900-05352 - Southeast Asia Studies Conference, 1990-1992 (Box 19, Folder 222)
  - Ford Foundation Grant #920-0417 - International Law and Global Environmental Change: A Systematic Study of International Environmental Accords, 1991-1993 (Box 19, Folder 223)
  - Ford Foundation HUD Roundtables, 1993-1994 (Box 19, Folder 224)
  - Ford Foundation Grant #930-0821 Sexuality Research, 1993 (Box 19, Folder 225)
  - Foundations - General, 1977-1980 (Box 19, Folder 226)
  - Pending Ford Proposal, 1990 February 2 (Box 19, Folder 227)
    SSRC/ACLS predoctoral fellowship program to link the social sciences and area studies
  - East European Politics - Ford Foundation Grant #845-0761, 1983-1984 (Box 19, Folder 228)
  - Ford Foundation Correspondence, 1973-1978 (Box 19, Folder 229)
  - Information Paper - The Foundation and the Less Developed Countries: The Decade of the Seventies, 1972 March (Box 20, Folder 230)
  - Ford International Fellowship Program Development Grant #620-0088, 1986-1990 (Box 20, Folder 231)
  - Family Poverty/Child Development - Foundation for Child Development, 1982-1990 (Box 20, Folder 232)
  - Foundation for Child Development Questionnaire, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 233)
  - Visit to Hewlett, 1993 (Box 20, Folder 234)
  - General Grants - Hewlett Foundation, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 235)
  - Grant Information - Japan-U.S. Friendship Commission, 1986-1995 (Box 20, Folder 236)
  - Korea Foundation, 1992-1993 (Box 20, Folder 237)
  - Ford Foundation - Peter de Janosi and Mariam Chamberlain, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 238)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) Draft - ACLS/SSRC International Research Program, 1985-1986 (Box 20, Folder 239)
  - Henry Luce Foundation, 1989-1994 (Box 20, Folder 240)
  - Polytechnic University, Brooklyn, New York, 1992 (Box 20, Folder 241)
  - Polish Volume, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 242)
  - Frederic Wakeman Research on Shanghai History, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 243)
  - Rural Sociology Board - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 244)
  - Marsha Mailick Seltzer Research, 1989-1990 (Box 20, Folder 245)
  - Columbia Seminar, 1986 (Box 20, Folder 246)
  - Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences, 1989-1993 (Box 20, Folder 247)
  - The Criterion of "Relevance" in the Support of Research in the Social Sciences, Cyril S. Smith and Otto N. Larsen - Social Science Research Council/Economic and Social Research Council Britain, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 248)
  - SSRC - Washington Office, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 249)
  - Universities Service Centre, 1988 (Box 21, Folder 250)
  - International Society for the Study of Behavioral Development, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 251)
  - Smithsonian and US Final Report on Research, 1981-1992 (Box 21, Folder 252)
  - Taiwan Trip - Academia Sinica, 1989 (Box 21, Folder 253)
  - Technology Transfer and Cognition, 1987 March (Box 21, Folder 254)
  - Stanford Talking Terrorism Project, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 255)
  - United Nations University (UNU)/SSRC Conference, 1985-1987 (Box 21, Folder 256)
  - UNESCO, 1987-1992 (Box 21, Folder 257)
  - Quantitative and Empirical Methodology File, 1987-1988 (Box 21, Folder 258)
  - American Cultural Diplomacy - Culture and Foreign Policy Conference, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 259)
  - Bosch Foundation, 1982 (Box 21, Folder 260)
  - Brookings Institution - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 21, Folder 261)
  - Bush Foundation, 1980-1981 (Box 21, Folder 262)
  - Bruner Foundation, Inc., 1982 (Box 21, Folder 263)
  - Carnegie Corporation, 1975-1985 (Box 21, Folder 264, Box 22, Folder 265)
  - Coolidge Center, 1987-1988 (Box 22, Folder 266)
  - Daewoo Foundation, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 267)
  - Charles A. Dana Foundation, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 268)
  - Charles A. Dana Foundation - Life-Course Committee, 1984-1987 (Box 22, Folder 269)
  - Economic and Social Research Council, London, England, 1980-1988 (Box 22, Folder 270)
  - Edna McConnell Clark Foundation, 1982-1983 (Box 22, Folder 271)
  - Milton S. Eisenhower Foundation, 1987 (Box 22, Folder 272)
  - Exxon Educational Foundation, 1980-1986 (Box 22, Folder 273)
  - Lynne and Harry Bradley Foundation, 1990 (Box 22, Folder 274)
  - Foundations General, 1985-1986 (Box 22, Folder 275)
  - An Annotated Bibliography on the History of American Foundations, Kathleen D. McCarthy, 1986 April (Box 22, Folder 276)
  - Academia Sinica, 1990-1991 (Box 22, Folder 277)
  - Adolescence, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 278)
  - Exxon Education Foundation - The Use of Personal Testimony in the Social Sciences and the Humanities, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 279)
  - Annual Report Requests, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 280)
  - Foundations - General, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 281)
  - Foundation Briefing Sheets, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 282-286)
  - The Foundation Center - General Information, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 287)
  - The National Humanities Center Application Material, 1981-1982 (Box 23, Folder 288)
  - Foundations - Miscellaneous Contributors Lists, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 289)
  - Joint Committee on Research Libraries, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 290)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1979-1992 (Box 23, Folder 291)
  - Guggenheim Memorial Foundation - Fellow-to-Fellow Fundraising Campaign, 1994 (Box 23, Folder 292)
  - Eugene Garfield Foundation, 1991 (Box 23, Folder 293)
  - Inter-American Foundation, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 294)
  - International University Foundation - International Conference: Cultural Preservation in Development, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 295)
  - Ittleson Foundation, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 296)
  - Kellogg Institute For International Studies, Notre Dame, 1987 (Box 23, Folder 297)
  - Kettering Foundation - Discussion Invitation, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 298)
  - The Lilly Endowment - Committee on the Comparative Study of Muslim Societies, 1989 (Box 23, Folder 299)
  - Linkages Colson Proposal - Joint Committee on African Studies, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 300)
  - Macmillan Foundation, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 301)
  - Markle Foundation, 1983-1989 (Box 23, Folder 302)
  - Markle Foundation - SSRC Panel on Computers and Contemporary Life, 1984-1992 (Box 23, Folder 303)
  - Matsushita International Foundation, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 304)
  - Andrew W. Mellon Foundation - Committee on Economic Stability and Growth, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 305)
  - MacArthur - Mid-Life Development, 1989 (Box 24, Folder 306)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 307)
  - National Institute For Aging, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 308)
  - National Institute of Mental Health, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 309)
  - National Academy of Sciences - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 24, Folder 310)
  - National Academy of Sciences - Government-University-Industry Research Roundtable Conference, 1986 February (Box 24, Folder 311)
  - National Academy of Sciences - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 312)
  - National Historical Publications and Records Commission, National Archives - Establishing An Archives at the Social Science Research Council proposal, 1985 (Box 24, Folder 313-314)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) - Council Committee on Personal Testimony, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 315)
  - Noyes Foundation, 1982 (Box 24, Folder 316)
  - National Science Foundation (NSF) - Data Confidentiality, Committee to Increase the Scientific Yield from the Federal Government's Survey of Income and Program Participation, 1986-1989 (Box 24, Folder 317)